<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Green Code</title>
    <link>https://greencode.codes/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Green Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 17:55:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://greencode.codes/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Electrons with Python</title>
      <link>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-electrons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 17:55:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-electrons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an atom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*2XmxyMo-tV9ZXC7CLUl4qg.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you observe, it has a central core formed of neutrons and protons. But they are also surrounded by tiny particles called electrons. These particles are arranged in different electron layers called &lt;strong&gt;shells&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most textbox images of atoms are static, so there’s a common subconscious misconception that atoms are static.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s far from reality. Both in the nucleus and especially in the electrons shells. The atoms that form us are in constant movement 24/7. They don’t stop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What do zebras and cholesterol have in common?</title>
      <link>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-zebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 18:12:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-zebra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*XKho4A270W0NbxgyiO5FKA.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth is filled with &lt;strong&gt;magnificent creatures&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;vast variety of ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt;. From gigantic elephants to unimaginable tiny creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of their tremendous differences, they are all ruled by the same &lt;strong&gt;ruthless laws of nature&lt;/strong&gt;. But, how do they work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does a cell know how much cholesterol has to be produced?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is the number of zebras regulated?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cellular-cholesterol-production&#34;&gt;Cellular cholesterol production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s right! &lt;strong&gt;Your body also produces cholesterol&lt;/strong&gt;. So, in reality, you have two sources of cholesterol: food and your own cells might produce it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Cell is Inside You</title>
      <link>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 18:12:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-cell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*mCZAH35osUtmbsoj3qesqA.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weird-looking cell is inside your body and it’s crucial for your survival. It’s called a &lt;strong&gt;dendritic cell.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also has a very interesting job: &lt;strong&gt;eating and vomiting stuff&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s right! The dendritic cell’s job is to go around your body and constantly intaking stuff and then vomiting it out. Very useful I know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s most useful when an infection is taking place. Once it encounters a bacteria, it swallows it and breaks it into pieces. If that wasn’t cruel enough, it starts displaying the bacteria pieces in its octopus-like tentacles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why papercuts won&#39;t kill you</title>
      <link>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-papercut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 17:55:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://greencode.codes/posts/2022-papercut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s nighttime. You’re relaxing at home reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hatching-Twitter-Story-Friendship-Betrayal/dp/1591847087/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;
  a book on Twitter’s invention
&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re lying on your comfy bed while enjoying some Silicon Valley drama and getting ready to sleep. And then the most horribly annoying thing happens. As you try to turn the page, the &lt;strong&gt;sharp edge of the page brushes against your skin&lt;/strong&gt;. You suddenly feel a sharp pain on the tip of your index finger. Alarmed you quickly look at it only to realize that it has happened again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
